Guide to the Office of the President records, 1795-2007 RG0002
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Annual reports of the President, 1888-1917, 1964-2000, 2007; Series 7; 2 Linear Feet 4 document boxes
  - GW Annual Report, 1984 (Box 264, Folder 5)
  - GW Annual Report, 1985 (Box 264, Folder 6)
  - GW Annual Report, 1986 (Box 264, Folder 7)
  - GW Annual Report, 1987 (Box 264, Folder 8)
  - GW Annual Report, 1988 (Box 264, Folder 9)
  - Report of the President, 1989 (Box 264, Folder 10)
  - Report of the President, 1990 (Box 264, Folder 11)
  - President's Report, 1991 (Box 264, Folder 12)
  - President's Report, 1992 (Box 264, Folder 13)
  - President's Report, 1993 (Box 265, Folder 1)
  - President's Report, 1994 (Box 265, Folder 2)
  - President's Report, 1995 (Box 265, Folder 3)
  - President's Report - The George Washington University 1987-1997: A Historic Decade (Box 265, Folder 4)
  - President's Report, 1998 (Box 265, Folder 5)
  - President's Report, 1999 (Box 265, Folder 6)
  - President's Report, 2000 (Box 265, Folder 7)
  - President's Report, 2003 (Box 265, Folder 9)
    Sketching a plan for the future
  - President's Report, 2005 (Box 265, Folder 10)
  - President's Report, 2007 (Box 265, Folder 8)
- Steven Knapp records, 2007; Series 8; 1.5 Linear Feet 1 record center carton
  Steven Knapp became the 16th president of the George Washington University in August 2007. His priorities include enhancing the university's partnerships with neighboring institutions, expanding the scope of its research, strengthening its worldwide community of alumni, enlarging its students' opportunities for public service, and leading its transformation into a model of urban sustainability.
  Dr. Knapp serves on the boards of the Economic Club of Washington; the Greater Washington Board of Trade; the Greater Washington Urban League; the World Affairs Council - Washington, DC; the National Symphony Orchestra; the Consortium of Universities of the Washington Metropolitan Area; the Washington National Cathedral Foundation; and Al Akhawayan University in Ifrane, Morocco. He is chair of the Atlantic 10 Conference Council of Presidents. He also serves as an honorary adviser to the Sulgrave Manor Trust, and is a member of the senior advisory board of the Northern Virginia Technology Council, the executive committee of the Council on Competitiveness, and the jobs committee of the Federal City Council.
  A specialist in Romanticism, literary theory, and the relation of literature to philosophy and religion, Dr. Knapp taught English literature at the University of California, Berkeley before serving as dean of arts and sciences and then provost of the Johns Hopkins University. He is a fellow of the American Academy of Arts and Sciences, a member of the Council on Foreign Relations, and a member of the Modern Language Association. The author of three books and numerous articles, he earned his doctorate and masters degrees from Cornell University and his Bachelor of Arts degree from Yale University.
  This series consists of materials related to the inauguration of Steven Knapp in 2007.
  - Knapp Inauguration Materials, 2007 (Box 266)
    Printed materials related to the celebration of the inaguration of President Knapp. Also includes one large banner and script from the inauguration ceremony.
  - Inauguration of Steven Knapp DVD, 2007 (Box 292, Folder 1)
  - Interview with Steven Knapp from "The Inner Loop" CD, 2010 (Box 292, Folder 2)
  - Carlos Slim Medal Presentation with President Knapp CD, 2009 (Box 292, Folder 3)
  - "Dr. Steven Knapp" interview with NBC Washington Office DVD, 2006 (Box 292, Folder 4)
  - "Steve Knapp and James Boyle" - Money for Breakfast interview on Fox Business DVD, 2007 (Box 292, Folder 5)
  - Colonials Weekend 2007 - a Conversation with Steven Knapp DVD (Box 292, Folder 6)
    Event was held in Lisner Auditorium.
- Thomas J. LeBlanc records, 2017-2021; Series 9
  Thomas J. LeBlanc was unanimously elected by The Board of Trustees of the George Washington University as the University's seventeenth President on January 6, 2017 and began his service to the University on August 1, 2017.
  An accomplished academic leader, Dr. LeBlanc previously served as the Executive Vice President, Provost and Professor of Computer Science and Electrical and Computer Engineering at the University of Miami. In that role he was both the Chief Academic Officer and the Chief Budget Officer, responsible for the University's ten schools and colleges, the library system, the Division of Student Affairs, the Division of Continuing and International Education, and undergraduate education, admissions and financial aid.
  In May 2021, Dr. LeBlanc announced that he would retire. On October 5, 2021, the Board of Trustees approved a resolution to honor Dr. LeBlanc's service to GW, awarding him the status of president emeritus at the conclusion of his term. Board of Trustees Chair Grace Speights commended Dr. LeBlanc's leadership through the pandemic and celebration of the University's bicentennial, highlighting his commitment to GW's medical enterprise, student experience, alumni engagement and student aid. He completed his presidency in December 2021.
  - Inauguration materials, 2017; RG0002 Series 9 Subseries 1 (Box 287, Box 288, Box 289, Box 290, Box 291)
    Certificates and correspondence sent by other universities on the occasion of President LeBlanc's inauguration.
    The materials in this subseries have been left in the same order as when they were transferred to Special Collections--possibly how the Office of the President received the certificates and correspodence or how they were boxed up. This subseries has been minimally processed, with some items being foldered when necessary.